<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Reflective Tech Consulting For Succesful Projects</title><subtitle>Helping others with useful content</subtitle>
  <link href="/rss.xml/" rel="self"/>
  <link href="/"/>
  <updated>2024-01-22T00:00:00Z</updated>
  <id>/</id>
  <author>
    <name></name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <title>The Seven Stages of Expertise in Software Engineering</title>
    <link href="/post/the-seven-stages-of-expertise-in-software-engineering/"/>
    <updated>2023-04-25T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>/post/the-seven-stages-of-expertise-in-software-engineering/</id> 
    <summary>This article is still **relevant for any startup or company involved in software development**. It contains useful informations - just like &quot;Clean Code&quot; by Robert C Martin - **details within this article are timeless**.

I first came across this article around 2016, when I noticed a large **disparity between the usual junior-mid-senior scaling** of developers. This scaling system, unlike others, is **universal**, easy to understand, and **the bear hunting analogy** used in the original article by Meilir Page-Jones makes it a **humorous and enjoyable read**.

Since then, the original page has been taken down (an archive can be found here). With the permission of the author, I am allowed to distribute the original article.

I made some slight changes by adding additional titles and styling. **Since there is more behind the seven stages, it is likely to be referenced frequently.**

**We hope you enjoy reading this article and that it helps your next projects be successful.**</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Effective Email Management for Busy Leaders</title>
    <link href="/post/effective-email-management-for-busy-leaders/"/>
    <updated>2023-11-08T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>/post/effective-email-management-for-busy-leaders/</id> 
    <summary>Efficient email management is a skill that can transform your daily routine and boost your team&#39;s productivity.
Take the time to refine your email habits, and watch your effectiveness soar!</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Effective Async Communication for Busy Leaders</title>
    <link href="/post/effective-async-communication-for-busy-leaders/"/>
    <updated>2023-11-09T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>/post/effective-async-communication-for-busy-leaders/</id> 
    <summary>Tired of constant interruptions?
Say goodbye to productivity killers!

Context switching in synchronous chat programs can be a real productivity killer, leading to increased interruptions and reduced efficiency.
But fear not, we&#39;ve got the solution to supercharge your work!</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Effective Meeting Rules</title>
    <link href="/post/effective-meeting-rules/"/>
    <updated>2023-11-10T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>/post/effective-meeting-rules/</id> 
    <summary>Meetings can be a pain—we&#39;ve all been there. The problem? They often lack a plan, decisions are last-minute, and real progress is rare. But fear not! Let&#39;s turn things around with these simple rules to make your meetings actually count!</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>When NOT to use Async Communication</title>
    <link href="/post/when-not-to-use-async-communication/"/>
    <updated>2023-11-22T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>/post/when-not-to-use-async-communication/</id> 
    <summary>Following my &quot;Story of staying in Prague&quot; I realized that, in addition to understanding how to make asynchronous communication work for you, recognizing when not to use asynchronous communication is equally crucial.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Getting started - Robert C. Martin - Clean-Code</title>
    <link href="/post/getting-started-robert-c.-martin-clean-code/"/>
    <updated>2024-01-05T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>/post/getting-started-robert-c.-martin-clean-code/</id> 
    <summary>**Knowing the right things** is the way to move forward **quickly** and produce **great results**.

This post is intended for developers eager to enhance their skills. It&#39;s equally valuable for **CEOs**, **CTOs**, **VPEs**, and **Technical Leads** who oversee a team and aspire to deliver **quality products**. Half of the videos do deal with management related-topics.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>John K. Ousterhout - A Philosophy of Software Design</title>
    <link href="/post/john-k.-ousterhout-a-philosophy-of-software-design/"/>
    <updated>2024-01-15T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>/post/john-k.-ousterhout-a-philosophy-of-software-design/</id> 
    <summary>Achieving **excellence** in software development demands a balanced mix of hands-on creativity and principled methodology. As a **leader** (CEO, founder, technical lead), you need to **figure out what works for you and your team**!

Now let&#39;s tackle &quot;software design&quot; again, from a slightly **different perspective**...</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Domain Driven Design and Refactoring</title>
    <link href="/post/domain-driven-design-and-refactoring/"/>
    <updated>2024-01-22T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>/post/domain-driven-design-and-refactoring/</id> 
    <summary>We have reached the 3rd part of our quality code series—now, let&#39;s talk about **Domain-Driven Design (DDD)**. Why does it matter? Because **we solve business problems**, and DDD tackles communication, coding/structure, and complexities in the software industry for an **easily maintainable, scalable solution**.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The Critical Choice - Picking the Perfect CTO Archetype for Your Business / Startup</title>
    <link href="/post/the-critical-choice-picking-the-perfect-cto-archetype-for-your-business-startup/"/>
    <updated>2023-10-31T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>/post/the-critical-choice-picking-the-perfect-cto-archetype-for-your-business-startup/</id> 
    <summary>**In a world where exceptional technical leadership can make or break a company, it&#39;s essential to consider the role of a Chief Technology Officer (CTO) with utmost care.**

Selecting the right CTO is a critical decision, one that can significantly impact your business at its current stage and align with the existing roles within your engineering team. The wrong choice can lead to friction, inefficiencies, and unnecessary expenses, while the right one can act as an enabler, streamlining processes, and facilitating seamless future development without additional sacrifices.

**Here&#39;s the good news:** you don&#39;t always need a _full-time_ CTO (and deep pockets) to get the tech expertise you need. Clear up some _common misconceptions_, match your CTO to your business, and watch it thrive.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>The Equity Fallacy</title>
    <link href="/post/the-equity-fallacy/"/>
    <updated>2023-11-06T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>/post/the-equity-fallacy/</id> 
    <summary>In the fast-paced world of startups, the journey to success is fraught with uncertainties. Startling statistics reveal that **only a mere 1% of startups manage to reach the coveted IPO stage**, with a significant number meeting their demise within the initial five years[^1].

The idea of working for equity alone is a double-edged sword, raising questions about the feasibility and motivations of those with extensive technical expertise considering this path.</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Rapid Byte Brilliance (RBB) Newsletter</title>
    <link href="/post/rapid-byte-brilliance-(rbb)-newsletter/"/>
    <updated>2023-12-21T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <id>/post/rapid-byte-brilliance-(rbb)-newsletter/</id> 
    <summary>Dear Esteemed **CEOs**, **CTOs**, **VPEs**, and **Technical Leads**, in forging the **excellence** of your software, the **pivotal role** played by your **architects** and **developers**, cannot be overstated.

Steer your team away from subpar videos and articles to **save their valuable time**. Ensure a trajectory of success by emphasizing that your developers **engage with top-tier learning materials**.

[Link to Newsletter posts](http://localhost:4300/category/newsletter/clean-code/1/)</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>
